givepulse.com 2018-11-06

# Policies | GivePulse

Last Updated: May 9, 2018 

This Privacy Policy provides our policies and procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing your information. Users can access the GivePulse service (the “Service”) through our website [www.givepulse.com](http://www.givepulse.com/ "GivePulse Home"), applications on Devices, through APIs, and through third-parties. A “Device” is any computer used to access the GivePulse Service, including without limitation a desktop, laptop, mobile phone, tablet, or other consumer electronic device. This Privacy Policy governs your access of the GivePulse Service, regardless of how you access it, and by using our Services you consent to the collection, transfer, processing, storage, disclosure and other uses described in this Privacy Policy. All of the different forms of data, content, and information described below are collectively referred to as “information.” 

### The Information We Collect and Store

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Site, Application, services, features and content, to administer your use of the Site and Application (together, the "Service") and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Site and Application. 

### Information You Provide

When you register an account, we collect some personal information, such as your name, phone number, t-shirt size, and email address. You may also ask us to import your contacts by giving us access to your third party services (for example, your email account) or to use your social networking information if you give us access to your account on social network connection services. When you invite others to join GivePulse by using our referral page, we send them a one-time email for that referral. You may also provide us with your contacts’ email addresses when sharing folders or files with them. We may also receive Personal Information (for example, your email address) through other users, for example if they have tried to share something with you or tried to refer GivePulse to you. 

When you register with us through the Site or Application and become a Member and when you choose to post/register to an Event, or when you wish to contact another Member or Organizer, we will ask you for personally identifiable information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you ("Identity Information"). Identity Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, and email address. 

We collect Personal Information in connection with your registration to join the Service. You can register to join via the Site or Application by completing the required forms. 

You can also register to join by logging into online accounts you may have with third party service providers ("SNS")(e.g. Facebook); each such account, a "Third Party Account", via our Site or Application as described below. As part of the functionality of the Site, Service and Application, you may link your GivePulse Account with Third Party Accounts, by either: (i) providing your Third Party Account login information to GivePulse through the Site, Service or Application; or (ii) allowing GivePulse to access your Third Party Account, as is permitted under the applicable terms and conditions that govern your use of each Third Party Account. You represent that you are entitled to disclose your Third Party Account login information to GivePulse and/or grant GivePulse access to your Third Party Account (including, but not limited to, for use for the purposes described herein), without breach by you of any of the terms and conditions that govern your use of the applicable Third Party Account and without obligating GivePulse to pay any fees or making GivePulse subject to any usage limitations imposed by the applicable SNS. If you decide to register by logging into a Third Party Account via our Site or Application, we will obtain the Personal Information you have provided to the applicable SNS (such as your "real" name, email address, profile picture, names of SNS friends, names of SNS groups to which you belong, other information you make publicly available via the applicable SNS and/or other information you authorize GivePulse to access by authorizing the SNS to provide such information) from your Third Party Accounts and use that information to create your GivePulse Account and GivePulse Account profile page and you will become a Member. Depending on the Third Party Accounts you choose and subject to the privacy settings that you have set in such Third Party Accounts, you understand that by granting us access to the Third Party Accounts, we will access, make available and store (if applicable and as permitted by the SNS and authorized by you) the information in your Third Party Accounts so that it is available on and through your GivePulse Account on the Site, Service and Application. If there is information about your "friends" or people with whom you are associated in your Third Party Account, the information we obtain about those "friends" or people with whom you are associated, may also depend on the privacy settings such people have with the applicable SNS. 

We also collect the other information that you provide as part of registration and the administration and personalization of your GivePulse Account profile (e.g., without limitation, zip code, emergency contact information, and education information, and individual preferences or demographic information) ("Non-Identifying Information"). 

We also use your Personal Information to contact you with GivePulse newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your "Notifications" information. (See "Changing or Deleting Information," below.) Please note that we may also use your Personal Information to contact you with information related to your use of the Service; you may not opt out of these notifications. 

By submitting Information through our Web site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your Information according to this Privacy Policy and you agree to the GivePulse Terms of Service located at <http://www.givepulse.com/site/terms> (the "Terms of Service"). Your Information may be processed by us in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country. 

### How We Use Personal Information

The Site, Application and Service can be used to facilitate the listing, registration and management of Events. Listings for such Events are made available via the Site, Application and Service by Organizers. Listings posted by Organizers, comments and reviews of Volunteers and Organizer, and the Profile Information Organizers and Volunteers, are visible to any GivePulse User. 

When you create a GivePulse Account, we will set up a GivePulse Account profile page for you. Your GivePulse Account profile page will include your first name and last initial. You can select the other items of Personal Information that you wish to be included in your GivePulse Account profile page – including, but not limited to, a profile picture, a list of the SNS groups to which you belong, a list of any of your SNS friends or connections who are also Members of GivePulse, connections you have established between your Account and any SNSs, and a biography and links to your Listings, if applicable (together, your "Profile Information"). We will display your Profile Information in your GivePulse Account profile page publicly via the Site and Application, and, with your prior permission, on third party sites. Any information you choose to provide as part of your Profile Information will be publicly visible to all GivePulse Users and consequently should reflect how much you want other GivePulse Users to know about you. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information and we encourage members to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their profile pages. You can review and revise your Profile Information at any time. 

If you post a Listing, we may publish that Listing publicly via the Site and Application and may enable third parties to publish your Listing on their websites through the use of an HTML "widget". 

### Children's Privacy

Our Services are not directed to persons under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse"). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will take steps to delete such information from our files. 

However, we welcome Volunteers of all ages, including children under the age of 13 by strongly encouraging our volunteers aged thirteen and under to use our services only with parental consent and supervision. 

### Changing or Deleting Your Information

All Members may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their registration profile by contacting us at terms@GivePulse.com or editing the relevant part of their profile. If you would like us to deactivate or delete your GivePulse Account, please contact us with the subject "Deactivate Account" or "Delete Account" and we will attempt to accommodate your request if we do not have any legal obligation or a legitimate business reason to retain the information contained in your GivePulse Account. Please note that, if you cancel your GivePulse Account, any comments you have posted via the Site and Application will remain publicly viewable via the Site and Application. Please see below for privacy contact information. 

### Log Data

When you use the Service, we automatically record information from your Device, its software, and your activity using the Services. This may include the Device’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, the web page visited before you came to our website, information you search for on our website, locale preferences, identification numbers associated with your Devices, your mobile carrier, date and time stamps associated with transactions, system configuration information, metadata concerning your Files, and other interactions with the Service. 

### Cookies

We also use “cookies” to collect information and improve our Services. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your Device. We may use “persistent cookies” to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Service. We may use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the Service, to better understand how you interact with the Service and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on the Service. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all aspects of the Service. 

### Web Beacons

Our Site and Application may contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our Site and Application are used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns. 

### Security

GivePulse is very concerned with safeguarding your information. When you enter sensitive information (such as emergency contact information) we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Site and Application, you can contact us.   
We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored "personal data" (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on the Site and Application in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system. 

### Links

This site may contain links to other sites. GivePulse is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

### Testimonials

With your consent we may post your testimonial on the Site and Application along with your name. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us. 

### How You Can Review Or Correct Your Information

If you are a nonprofit member or volunteer with a personal GivePulse account (either through [www.givepulse.com](http://www.givepulse.com/ "GivePulse Home") or a Partner's Web site) you may review and make changes to all of your Information that we collect and maintain online by simply inputting your username and password where indicated on the Web site.   
If you are a volunteer with a personal GivePulse account, once you login in, you may make any changes or correct factual errors in your account by changing the information on your login page. This option is available 24 hours a day to better safeguard your Information, subject to downtime for standard maintenance and support. You do not need to contact us to access your record or to make any changes. If you have problems changing your Information, please contact Community Services at [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse"). 

### For Nonprofit or Other Volunteer Agencies

If you are an Agency administrator, you may make any changes or correct factual errors in your administrator, organization and Event information 24 hours a day. We use this procedure to better safeguard your Information. You do not need to contact us to access your record or to make any changes. If you have problems changing your Agency's Information, please contact Community Services at [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse").   
If you are a nonprofit member or volunteer with an account and would like to have your Information deleted from the site, you may do so by contacting Community Services at [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse"). 

### Opting-out of Newsletters & Communications

Subscriptions to GivePulse newsletters are optional and GivePulse allows Agencies, volunteers, subscribers or other users to unsubscribe from newsletters at any time. In each newsletter we provide instructions regarding how to opt-out from receiving future newsletter mailings. You can also email us at [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse") to remove your name from our newsletter subscription data base and ensure that you will cease receiving future newsletters from us.   
We may also use our email lists for sending out other GivePulse outbound communications such as product enhancements, tool upgrades, or membership news. Registered members are required to receive these communications. 

### How To Contact Us

We appreciate your questions or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with GivePulse. Please send email to [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse")

### Changes to Policy

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. If we make a change to this privacy policy that we believe materially reduces your rights, we will provide you with notice (for example, by email). And we may provide notice of changes in other circumstances as well. By continuing to use the Service after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.  

### Hosted Solution

Note: Institutions, nonprofits, businesses and partners who purchase a subscription can enter into a contract in which the terms of the Agreement shall control. In all instances, this relates to protecting data of student, employee, and staff to the highest regard. For further information, please email [support@givepulse.com](mailto:support@givepulse.com "Contact Us @ GivePulse") or your institution's contract, legal or data owner.
